Finding aid of the Herbert Hutchinson Brimley Photograph Collection, 1880-1977 PHC.42
State Archives of North Carolina
Herbert Hutchinson Brimley Photograph Collection
1880-1977
PHC.42
PhC.42
15.0 cubic feet (approximately 5,000 items)
15.00 5000.00
The Brimley Collection is named for Herbert Hutchinson Brimley, the first Curator (and later, first Director) of The North Carolina State Museum of Natural History. Brimley was born in Bedfordshire, England, on 7 March 1861 and immigrated with his parents to Raleigh in the winter of 1880. During his years of service with the State Museum, Brimley assembled North Carolina displays at various national and international expositions. In preparation of his exhibits for the various shows, Brimley did his own photographic work and traveled throughout North Carolina to capture scenes for display in his exhibits. This collection includes photographic negatives and prints taken and overseen by Herbert Hutchinson Brimley (1861-1946) for the Department of Agriculture, the North Carolina Geological Survey and the State Museum. The photographs document many aspects of life in the state between the late Nineteenth and early Twentieth centuries.
Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
State Archives of North Carolina
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Agriculture: Cattle, Corn, Field Crops 1-10
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Agriculture: Field Crops 11-49, General, Hogs
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Agriculture: Lettuce, Poultry, Sheep, Strawberries 1-10
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Agriculture: Strawberries 11-19, Tobacco, Wheat; Airplanes, and Archaeology
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Art, Birds, Boats and Boating 1-5
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Boats and Boating 6-30, Bodies of Water, Bogue Sound and Banks, Botanical Specimens, Bridges, C. S. Brimley, and H. H. Brimley
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Business and Industry, Camps and Camping, Cape Hatteras 1-50
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Cape Hatteras 51-81, Chimneys and Stoves, Cities: New Bern, Cities: Raleigh 1-15
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Cities: Raleigh 16-74, Cities: Wilmington
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Cities: Non-NC, Coastal Scenes, Coast Guard, Courthouses, Harry T. Davis, Dismal Swamp, Distillation, Erosion, Expositions; Boston-Jamestown
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Expositions: New Orleans-Miscellaneous, Farmers Institute, Fish and Fishing 1-40
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Fish and Fishing 41-56, Fish Hatcheries, Fisheries, Fishing Camps
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Flowers and Plants, Food, Forestry and Forest Industries, 1-50
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Forestry and Forest Industries 51-91, Forts, Fruits and Orchards 1-16
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Fruits and Orchards 17-32, Geology, Geology: Meteorites
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Great Lake, History, Home Canning, Horses, Hotels and Motels.
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Hunting, Hunting camps, Hunting Clubs, Indians, Individuals, Invertebrates, Lake Junaluska, Lake Mattamuskeet, Lake Phelps, Lake Waccamaw, Maps, Marine Life, Military, Mills; Grist, Minerals.
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Mines and Mining, Miscellaneous, Museum of Natural History 1-10.
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Museum of Natural History 11-39
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Museum of Natural History 40-92, Museums Miscellaneous, North Carolina Shell Club.
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; N. C. State Exposition, 1884, North Carolina State Fair, Orton Plantation, Postcards
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Pottery, Scenic Central North Carolina
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Scenic Coastal Plain of NC, Scenic Western NC 1-47
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Scenic Western NC 48-114
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Scenic Western NC 115-175
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Scenic Western NC 176-237
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Schools, Sharks and Rays, Smith's Island, Sport Fishing 1-33
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Sport Fishing 34-53, Structures, Tools and Implements, Unidentified, White Lake, Windmills, World War II Era.
Box H. H. Brimley Photo Collection; Scenic Western NC 238-288, Schuyler Soapstone Factory
Access Restrictions
Available for research
Biographical/Historical note
Even before the end of Reconstruction in 1877, North Carolina had begun promoting the advantages of the state in an effort to attract new residents and investment capital. Photography, as an emerging technology in that era, was incorporated into the efforts to document the resources of the state. The North Carolina Geological Survey and the North Carolina Department of Agriculture were the agencies of state government involved in these promotional activities, and The State Museum, formed in 1879, became the repository for the joint collection of photographs.
The Brimley Collection is named for Herbert Hutchinson Brimley, the first Curator (and later, first Director) of The North Carolina State Museum of Natural History. Brimley was born in Bedfordshire, England, on 7 March 1861 and immigrated with his parents to Raleigh in the winter of 1880. His first night in the city was spent in the National Hotel, the building bought the following year for the new home of the North Carolina Department of Agriculture and the site of Brimley's work for the next 60 years. During his years of service with the State Museum, Brimley assembled North Carolina displays at various national and international expositions. In preparation of his exhibits for the various shows, Brimley did his own photographic work, and traveled throughout North Carolina to capture scenes for display in his exhibits.
H.H. Brimley took many of the photographs in the collection himself, and he was involved in all aspects of the work in which the photographs were used. His hiring in 1884 by S.G. Worth to prepare fish specimens for the Fisheries Exhibit at the North Carolina State Exposition coincides closely with the beginning of routine photographic work by the Department of Agriculture, and two photographs in the collection, although they are of poor quality, show that exhibit. The photographs in the Brimley Collection were used in the state's exhibits at numerous expositions. They were displayed framed and hung on the walls or, in the case of the Boston Food Fair, secured along the edges of the cases and mounted on matboard sheets that visitors could peruse. However, they also contributed to the expositions by providing illustrations for the various publications available at the exhibit's desk.
When Brimley died in 1946 at the age of 85, he was still an active state employee. After his death, the photographs remained at the Museum of Natural History for in house use by the museum staff. Under the directorship of Harry Towles Davis (1897-1978), the collection increased in size, and continued to be used in various exhibits and publications. Due to a lack of space and poor storage conditions, the Museum of Natural History transferred the collection to the State Archives in 1962 for permanent preservation.
Acquisitions Information
The collection was acquired on May 19, 1982 from the North Carolina Department of Agriculture, Office of Agri-Business, Museum of Natural History, Raleigh, NC.
Related Collections
Additional information on topics found in this collection may be found in the Manuscript and Archives Reference System (MARS) http://mars.archives.ncdcr.gov/BasicSearch.aspx
Scope and Contents note
This collection of photographic negatives and prints is made up of the photographs taken and overseen by Herbert Hutchinson Brimley (1861-1946) for the Department of Agriculture, the North Carolina Geological Survey and the State Museum. Images in the collection include glass plate negatives, film negatives, and a number of different types of original prints in a variety of sizes.
An accomplished photographer, Brimley's photographs document many aspects of life in the state between the late Nineteenth and early Twentieth centuries. Between the time the earliest photographs in the collection were taken, probably around 1870, and World War I, these pictures were alternately on the road representing North Carolina abroad and in other states or were on exhibit in the State Museum. They also furnished illustrations for numerous state publications and were useful in the other programs of the agencies. Between the end of Reconstruction in 1877 and 1917 the collection grew rapidly. The photographs in this early collection show North Carolina as its leaders wanted the state to be seen; they wanted to encourage the development of an abundant resource base, and they were unselfconscious in presenting a picture of scenery, people, and life. In these pictures things just are what they are; no social agenda other than the betterment of North Carolina through growth and progress is espoused. After World War I the nature of the collection changed. Rather than continuing to make collections of natural resource pictures, the Museum photographers concentrated, for the most part, on the narrower field of in-house museum life, exhibit preparation, and various day-to-day activities.
Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
Cape Hatteras Light Station (N.C.).; North Carolina Geological and Economic Survey.; North Carolina Geological Survey (1883-1905).; North Carolina. Department of Agriculture.; North Carolina. State Museum.
Agriculture--North Carolina; Archaeology--North Carolina; Birds--North Carolina; Boats and boating; Fish; Fishing--North Carolina; Forests and forestry; Fruit; Geology--North Carolina; Landscapes--North Carolina; Mines and mineral resources; Mountains--North Carolina--Pictorial works; Museums--North Carolina--Exhibitions--History; Ocean life; Orchards; Photographers--North Carolina
North Carolina--Social life and customs--19th century--Pictorial works; North Carolina--Social life and customs--20th century--Pictorial works
Lantern slides; Negatives (photographic); Photographic postcards
- Agriculture: Cattle, PhC.42.AgriCattle; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Newborn Calf, Cape Hatteras, NC, 1903. (2), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Dairy Cattle, Haw River, NC, ca. 1910 (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F10; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Aunt Betsy Holmes and "Joe" the bull, ca. 1905.She died in 1906, she was 80 plus years., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F11; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Horse and Cattle, Melville Farms, Haw River, 1910 (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F12; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Horse and Cattle, Melville Farms, Haw River, 1910 (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F13; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Holstein Cattle near New Bern, NC, c. 1910. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F14; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Dairy Cow, Bob Scott's, Melville Farm (same as folder 9) c. 1909 (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F15; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cows, Myrtle Hill Farm, Cumberland Co., NC, 1910 (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F16; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cow, "Eminent Lass" Pender Co., NC, 1922 (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F17; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cattle, Cox Farm, Rutherford Co., NC, n.d., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F18; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cows crossing dam, Scott Farm, Haw River, NC, c. 1900 (35mm n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F19; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Scrub Cow in front yard, Cape Hatteras, NC, c. 1901, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Dairy Herd, Fayetteville, NC, n.d. (2), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F20; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Summer grazing on mountain bald, c. 1906. (N.76.8.326), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F21; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Malformed calf, Asheville, NC, 1899, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F22; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cows grazing near Burnsville, NC, c. 1900. (2) (N.83.6.115), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F23-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cows grazing near Burnsville, NC, c. 1900. (2) (N.83.6.115), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F23-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Guernsey Cows, Owned by, Dr. H. T. Bahnson farm, Salem, NC., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F24; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cattle in Pocosin, Craven Co., NC, c. 1905., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F25; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cattle on "open grounds," Carteret Co., NC, c. 1907, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F26; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Working steer in western N.C. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F27; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cattle under tree, n.d., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F28; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Dairy herd of Holsteins, Craven Co., NC.(1)(n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F29; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Scrub Cow, Cape Hatteras, NC, ca. 1901, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F3; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Boy seated on bull, n.d. (N.83.6.117), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F30; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Herd of cattle grazing, n.d., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F31; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Calf, picket fence and house in background, Cape Hatteras, Dare County, NC, n.d., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F32; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Calf and Chickens, Cape Hatteras, NC, 1900-1903, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F4; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Calf, Cape Hatteras, NC, 1900-1903 (2), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F5-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Calf, Cape Hatteras, NC, 1900-1903 (2), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F5-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Scrub Cow, Cape Hatteras, NC, 1900-1903, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F6; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Wild Scrub Bull, Cape Hatteras, NC, 1900-1903, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F7; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Scrub Heifer, Cape Hatteras, NC, 1900-1903. (2), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F8; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Dairy Cow, Bob Scott's, Melville Farm, Haw River, NC, ca. 1910. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCattle.F9; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
- Agriculture: Corn, PhC.42.AgriCorn; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Ten corn ears. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F10; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Two corn ears, good and poor. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F11; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn ears, ca. 1908. (5), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F1-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Field of corn, near Raleigh, NC. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F12; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn ears, ca. 1908. (5), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F1-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn in mountain valley, western N.C.(1)(n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F13; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn ears, ca. 1908. (5), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F1-3; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn ears, ca. 1908. (5), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F1-4; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn ears, ca. 1908. (5), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F1-5; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Charlie Parker with pile of corn (235.5 bushels), grown on one acre of ground summer of 1911, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Mountain farm w/ cornfield, c. 1907, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F3; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Tip end of corn ear. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F4; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn, Buncombe Co., NC Farm. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F5; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Butt of corn ear. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F6; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Ear of corn grown by Charlie Parker. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F7; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Butt of two corn ears. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F8; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Corn Field near Raleigh, NC. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriCorn.F9; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
- Coastal Scenes, PhC.42.Coastal; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Wrightsville Beach and Cottages, 1906. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Ocracoke Lighthouse, ca. 1890., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F10; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Waterfront at Belhaven, NC, ca. 1900. (2) (1n) (cyan), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F11; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Two men in front of buildings surrounded by cannon balls., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F12; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Frazer Peele, fisherman, Hatteras, 1931., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F13; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Lake Michigan, Chicago, IL., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F14; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Palmetto tree, Smith's Island, 1920. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F15; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Seagulls flying over the coast. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F16-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Seagulls flying over the coast. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F16-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Ocracoke, NC, 1939., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F17; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Ocean Pier, Wrightsville Beach, 1910. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F18; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Palmetto trees, Smith's Island, 1913. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F19; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Surf at Wrightsville Beach, 1906. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Burial Mound Excavation, Topsail Inlet, 1928. Skeleton Burial Mound *original category "Mammals- Cetesia", PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F20-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Burial Mound Excavation, Topsail Inlet, 1928. Excavating Buried Bones *original category "Mammals- Cetesia", PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F20-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Burial Mound Excavation, Topsail Inlet, 1928. Topsail Inlet Camp *original category "Mammals- Cetesia", PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F20-3; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Burial Mound Excavation, Topsail Inlet, 1928. Bone Burial Pit *original category "Mammals- Cetesia", PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F20-4; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Burial Mound Excavation, Topsail Inlet, 1928. Bones to Mainland *original category "Mammals- Cetesia", PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F20-5; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Burial Mound Excavation, Topsail Inlet, 1928. Topsail Inlet *original category "Mammals- Cetesia", PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F20-6; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Burial Mound Excavation, Topsail Inlet, 1928. Topsail Inlet Beach Excavating Buried skeleton *original category "Mammals- Cetesia", PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F20-7; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Exposed Human Remains, Coastal Graveyard., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F21; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Coastline at Wrightsville Beach, NC., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F22; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Oyster Factory. (cyan), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F23; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-10; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-11; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-12; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-13; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-14; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-15; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-16; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-3; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-4; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-5; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-6; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-7; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-8; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - M. A. York River Place, Smyrna, NC, 1957. (17), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F24-9; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Three unidentified Coastal Scenes., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F25-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Three unidentified Coastal Scenes., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F25-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Wrightsville Beach and Cottages, 1906. (n), PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F3; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Northeast branch of the Cape Fear River, ca. 1890s., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F4; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Yeopon Tree, Wilmington, NC, 1890., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F5; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Lost Colony Monument, Roanoke Island, ca. 1899., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F6; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Unidentified Waterfront scene., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F7; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - House at Ocracoke, NC, 1915., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F8; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - "Lost Colony" Amphitheater, Manteo, NC, 1939., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F9-1; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - "Lost Colony" Amphitheater, Manteo, NC, 1939., PhC.42.Bx10.Coastal.F9-2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
- Agriculture: Field Crops, PhC.42.AgriField; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Pretty Baby in a Cotton Patch, Wake Co., NC, ca. 1905., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F10; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Peas and potatoes, Washington, NC. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F2; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Peanut fields, Wallace, NC, 1906. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F3; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Field of cabbage, D. L. Chadwick, Wilmington, NC, ca. 1903-1904., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F4; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Field of white potatoes, Wilmington, NC, ca. 1906., PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F5; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Faded Cyan Print of negative in folder 9, PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F6; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Field of early peas, New Bern, NC. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F7; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Pea Field, New Bern, NC. (n), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F8; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Asparagus, Eastern N.C. (n)(same as folder 6), PhC.42.Bx1.AgriField.F9; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Typical Cotton Field, Wake Co., NC, ca. 1906., PhC.42.Bx2.AgriField.F11; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Cabbage Field, New Bern, NC, ca. 1907., PhC.42.Bx2.AgriField.F12; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Mountain scene and field, ca. 1906., PhC.42.Bx2.AgriField.F13; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Bermuda Onions, Wilmington, NC, ca. 1904, PhC.42.Bx2.AgriField.F14; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Truck Crops, Newport, NC, ca. 1904., PhC.42.Bx2.AgriField.F15; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Oat Fields, Rowan Co., NC, ca. 1908., PhC.42.Bx2.AgriField.F16; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946
  - Potato Field, Pamlico Co., NC, ca. 1908., PhC.42.Bx2.AgriField.F17; Brimley, Herbert Hutchinson, 1861-1946